<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Group id="Fluid" name="Fluid examples">
    <Example id="SodShockTube2D" app="CompressibleFluid" logo="logo_sod.png" name="Sod shock tube 2D" dim="2D" cmd="::CompressibleFluid::examples::SodShockTube::Init">
        <Description>This is a 2D simulation of the classical Sod shock tube benchmark using the Euler equations.
Shock tube is a long tube with contant cross section, where a diaphragm separates the left and right halves that are filled with two different pressures 
of air. This diaphragm is located at x=0.5.
The gas in the left portion is higher pressure than the one on the right.
The problem geometry consists in a rectangular domain, 1 unit long and 0.1 units wide, with free-slip conditions on long sides and open boundaries on 
the short sides. 
The Sod shock problem is one-dimensional, which coincides with the X-axis in this case. Hence, no variations along the Y-axis are observed.
        </Description>
    </Example>
    <Example id="Wedge" app="CompressibleFluid" logo="logo_wedge.png" name="Wedge 2D" dim="2D" cmd="::CompressibleFluid::examples::Wedge::Init">
        <Description>This is a classical 2D simulation of a supersonic flow over a wedge using the Euler equations. 
The supersonic flow will create an oblique shock over the wedge that reach a stedy state very quickly.
The geometry is a Wedge with an angle of 21.5° in a rectangular domain. The Wedge and bottom boundaries are free-slip. The right and top boundaries are 
left open and the left boundary enforces same values as the initial conditions.
        </Description>
    </Example>
    <Example id="Step" app="CompressibleFluid" logo="logo_step.png" name="Step 2D" dim="2D" cmd="::CompressibleFluid::examples::Step::Init">
        <Description>This is a 2D simulation of the classical step from Woodward and Collela using the Euler equations.
The problem geometry consists of a rectangle with a step at the bottom. The rectangular domain has a width of 3 units and a height of 1 unit. The step 
is located 0.6 units to the right of the bottom-left corner, and it rises to 0.1 units above the bottom edge.
The top and bottom boundaries, as well as the step are free-slip. The node at the bottom of the step (0.6, 0.0), has its velocity set to zero for 
numerical stability purposes. 
The right boundary is left open and the left boundary enforces same values as the initial conditions.
        </Description>
    </Example>
</Group>
